<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ux Design on Black &amp; Light</title>
    <link>/tags/ux-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ux Design on Black &amp; Light</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ux-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of UX and a Guided Introduction</title>
      <link>/2016/07/08/pokemon-go-ux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/07/08/pokemon-go-ux/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the UX of Pokemon Go As with everyone else I picked up Pokemon Go when it released in the US this Wednesday. After pouring more than a couple hours in to it, and talking with a lot of people I have a few thoughts on the UX of the app and how it could be improved.
Guided Introduction Issues When you load up the game you&amp;rsquo;re dropped directly into the game (when the servers load, but that&amp;rsquo;s a whole different issue).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Divide</title>
      <link>/2015/04/25/bridging-the-gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 22:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/04/25/bridging-the-gap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;##Bridging the ‘Handoff’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uxreactions.com&#34;&gt;uxreactions.com&lt;/a&gt;
While I appreciate a lot of what is on the site, I must say; seeing the number of developer complaints make me very sad. I also noticed this trend at a recent meetup I attended. A large number of designers; UX, visual, IxD, voiced a number of complaints about developers. I’ve heard the same from developers about designers. I think this is an artifact of traditional waterfall approaches and the ‘hand off’. If we want to grow as teams and communities I think we need to stop complaining about each other and finding ways to bridge the gap. Sometimes an overly decorative design really does affect performance, and a slow experience is a poor experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>