<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on Black &amp; Light</title>
    <link>/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on Black &amp; Light</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 21:58:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone has a Hammer, No one sees the Nail</title>
      <link>/2016/06/21/everyone-has-a-hammer-no-one-sees-the-nail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 21:58:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/06/21/everyone-has-a-hammer-no-one-sees-the-nail/</guid>
      <description>Struggling with UX and Development There was a recent conversation in the UX Community on Slack Designer Hangout about getting developers to follow wireframes from a UX team. I’ve seen this question, and struggles come up hundreds of times in the last couple years.
 My ux team recently has been dealing with front-end developers deciding that they are designers &amp;amp; that ux wireframes are just a loose guideline. It’s been frustrating, because the development ends up having a lot of ux &amp;amp; usability issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hamburger Menu Is Not The Enemy</title>
      <link>/2015/08/11/the-hamburger-menu-is-not-the-enemy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 21:58:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/11/the-hamburger-menu-is-not-the-enemy/</guid>
      <description>Another anti-hamburger menu article is making it&amp;rsquo;s rounds again. This time from deep.design. A simple google search returns a number of articles about how the design pattern is a &amp;ldquo;useless tool&amp;rdquo; and should be avoided at all costs. I&amp;rsquo;m going to argue that the ideas behind the design pattern are neither useless nor harmful.
The issue most often brought up is that you can&amp;rsquo;t use what you can&amp;rsquo;t see; and that a user is not likely to go searching for an option they&amp;rsquo;re not even sure exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blind3y3Design 3.0</title>
      <link>/2015/08/07/blind3y3design-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/07/blind3y3design-30/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the new Blind3y3Design! &amp;ldquo;3.0? What happened to 2.0?&amp;rdquo; you say? Here&amp;rsquo;s the deal; after about 4 months of this site being on vanilla Jekyll I decided to switch over to using Octopress. It was great and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to change much to get it working. The one thing that kept nagging at me was the design. The layout and design of octopress is generally a good layout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The High Horse Mentality</title>
      <link>/2015/05/12/the-high-horse-mentality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 22:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/05/12/the-high-horse-mentality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spurred by &lt;a href=&#34;http://notlaura.com/&#34;&gt;Lara Schenck&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://css-tricks.com/tales-of-a-non-unicorn-a-story-about-the-trouble-with-job-titles-and-descriptions/&#34;&gt;CSS-Tricks&lt;/a&gt; I have decided to toss my two cents in to the bountiful fountain of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems the age of &amp;lsquo;Unicorns&amp;rsquo; has spawned a number of people who wind up simply being pricks sitting on their high horses. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying that people who claim to be unicorns are those people, or that they&amp;rsquo;re wholly guilt free either. It just seems the issue has bubbled to the surface more apparently in the recent past.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The #Talkpay Hashtag</title>
      <link>/2015/05/03/lets-talkpay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 22:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/05/03/lets-talkpay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something interesting happened on twitter this week. The #Talkpay hastag went viral. This sparked a number of conversations I had with my peers. On the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.designerhangout.co/&#34;&gt;User Experience Design&lt;/a&gt; Slack channel we spent a good while talking about the idea, and it&amp;rsquo;s potential ramifications or benefits to the community. So, let&amp;rsquo;s #Talkpay.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Divide</title>
      <link>/2015/04/25/bridging-the-gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 22:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/04/25/bridging-the-gap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;##Bridging the ‘Handoff’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uxreactions.com&#34;&gt;uxreactions.com&lt;/a&gt;
While I appreciate a lot of what is on the site, I must say; seeing the number of developer complaints make me very sad. I also noticed this trend at a recent meetup I attended. A large number of designers; UX, visual, IxD, voiced a number of complaints about developers. I’ve heard the same from developers about designers. I think this is an artifact of traditional waterfall approaches and the ‘hand off’. If we want to grow as teams and communities I think we need to stop complaining about each other and finding ways to bridge the gap. Sometimes an overly decorative design really does affect performance, and a slow experience is a poor experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a Workflow and Team Dynamic</title>
      <link>/2014/06/08/designing-a-team-dynamic-and-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 11:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/06/08/designing-a-team-dynamic-and-workflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The idea behind designing a single workflow is that at any time someone else should be able to jump in to your workflow and know where in the process you are and pick up after you in needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum and the Agile Philosophy</title>
      <link>/2014/06/08/scrum-and-the-agile-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 05:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/06/08/scrum-and-the-agile-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developing our own Agile process is something that we should take pride in. We can take bits and pieces from frameworks and create something that works for our team. The point is not to go whole hog in to a single framework and force the team to work inside the constraints predefined for a different team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>