<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on Blind3y3Design</title>
    <link>/categories/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on Blind3y3Design</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SPA Resume project</title>
      <link>/2016/07/11/resume-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/07/11/resume-project/</guid>
      <description>This project was inspired by the JSON resume project. The idea is that you create a standard JSON-based dataset, and then you can easily reuse that data across a multitide of templates without having to re-write your resume each time you wanted to update the look and feel. Any time you need to update any relevant data you can simply update the JSON and that data is accessible anywhere.
Read more about the JSON resume project here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broadway Collection</title>
      <link>/2015/12/31/broadway-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/12/31/broadway-collection/</guid>
      <description>The Broadway Collection site came with a unique set of problems we had to solve. First and foremost they had to be a neutral party in relation to all of the shows they feature on their site. Secondly, the site is translated into 5 different languages and is updated through a CMS.
In order to solve the first issue we came up with a couple of ideas. The easiest was obviously to list all of the shows in alphabetical order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York International Auto Show 2016</title>
      <link>/2015/12/31/new-york-auto-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/12/31/new-york-auto-show/</guid>
      <description>The goal with the New York International Auto Show site for 2016 was to present an experience as modern and sleek as the cars that were being presented.
We created a massive vehicle gallery for them, categorizing each vehicle by make and model. The pages were then dynamically generated based on information on the vehicles stores in JSON format. You could sort the vehicles by category, style, and manufacturer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>See Forever - One World Observatory</title>
      <link>/2015/12/31/see-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/12/31/see-forever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;See Forever at the One World Observatory in New York City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blind3y3Design 3.0</title>
      <link>/2015/08/07/blind3y3design-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/07/blind3y3design-30/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the new Blind3y3Design! &amp;ldquo;3.0? What happened to 2.0?&amp;rdquo; you say? Here&amp;rsquo;s the deal; after about 4 months of this site being on vanilla Jekyll I decided to switch over to using Octopress. It was great and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to change much to get it working. The one thing that kept nagging at me was the design. The layout and design of octopress is generally a good layout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gladiator GarageWorks Sale Page</title>
      <link>/2014/04/01/gladiator-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 10:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/04/01/gladiator-sale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The gladiator sale page takes data from a JSON file and transforms it in to a massive listing of all the products on sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every garage deserves a Gladiator</title>
      <link>/2014/04/01/gladiator-ecommerce/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/04/01/gladiator-ecommerce/</guid>
      <description>A large portion of the work we do is creating maintaining and updating content on client sites like this one. Personal responsibilities can be anything from updating a JSON file to pull new ads or putting a product feed on a page, to creating completely new and custom pages for a specific product, event, or promotion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vine Lights: Inorganic Life Series</title>
      <link>/2014/01/11/vine-lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 20:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/01/11/vine-lights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The work Vine Lights was an experimental piece in a series of works called &amp;ldquo;Inorganic Life.&amp;rdquo; The works themselves try to take things that are clearly inorganic in nature however when constructed in such a way they become in a sense a representation of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blind3y3Design Version 1.0.0</title>
      <link>/2014/01/08/blind3y3design-is-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/01/08/blind3y3design-is-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yay! We&amp;rsquo;re up and running using &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. It took some time and has quite a learning curve, but if you&amp;rsquo;re even remotely comfortable with the command line and you want to create a &amp;ldquo;simple, blog-aware static site&amp;rdquo; then it could be the thing for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Cookmore</title>
      <link>/2013/11/03/working-with-cookmore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 14:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/11/03/working-with-cookmore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my time at Aisle Rocket Studios I have had the immense pleasure of working on the site Cookmore.com. Cookmore is a community based cooking site. Regular people, as well as professional chefs can post recipes on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspirational Blogging</title>
      <link>/2013/11/03/kenmore-inspiration-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 12:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/11/03/kenmore-inspiration-blog/</guid>
      <description>The Kenmore Ispiration Blog is a community site that collects posts from across the web and combines them with posts by Kenmore and Cookmore. The blog is a community where people can share, post, and learn about all things Kenmore related.
Inspiration is build on a highly customized WordPress installation that is continually being built and improved upon. We recently set up new pages for contests like the “Couponista” challenge. This page followed 3 bloggers in their competition to be the greatest couponer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping Something Small</title>
      <link>/2013/11/03/kenco-small-parcel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/11/03/kenco-small-parcel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Small Parcel page on Kenco was a unique project when I got to work on it. It was my first experience usning the ExpressionEngine CMS. This page is build by creating a page template and once the templace is set and attached to a page we begin loading content on to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For the Craftsman in You</title>
      <link>/2013/11/03/craftsman-ecommerce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 11:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/11/03/craftsman-ecommerce/</guid>
      <description>A large portion of the work we do is creating maintaining and updating content on client sites like this one. Personal responsibilities can be anything from updating a JSON file to pull new ads or putting a product feed on a page, to creating completely new and custom pages for a specific product, event, or promotion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tested for Living</title>
      <link>/2013/11/03/kenmore-ecommerce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 11:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/11/03/kenmore-ecommerce/</guid>
      <description>A large portion of the work we do is creating maintaining and updating content on client sites like this one. Personal responsibilities can be anything from updating a JSON file to pull new ads or putting a product feed on a page, to creating completely new and custom pages for a specific product, event, or promotion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brand Names at Outlet Prices</title>
      <link>/2013/11/03/whirlpool-outlet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 00:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/11/03/whirlpool-outlet/</guid>
      <description>Most of the work done was largely edits to the CSS files that control the look of the site. We also edited and moved some of the HTML structure in order to better the document flow and user experience.
We recently Added a pop up modal to the homepage which uses an ajax request and API call to send and receive information from another web server. We solved some issues with IE8 by using the XMLHttpRequest function for IE.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>